# Santiago Serrato

https://linkedin.com/in/santiagoserrato | https://github.com/santiagoserratosantiagoserrato@gmail.com | (214) 714 - 4533

## Summary

Enthusiastic Software Developer with excellent communication skills and a strong motivation to succeed. Detail-oriented with strong technical skills and the ability to learn concepts quickly. Ambitious software developer with excellent research, time management and problem solving skills.

#### Skills

- PHP, Javascript, .Net, C/C++, Java, React, ¡Query, Bootstrap, HTML/CSS, MySQL, SQL, JSON, XML, Linux CLI
- Version control systems: Git and TortoiseSvn

### Work Experience

#### NRG Energy (acquired Stream Energy in August 2019), Software Development Team Lead

March 2018 - Present

- Supported and maintained Stream's Customer Information System for Texas (CIS1)
- Led a team of 2 developers; this consisted on planning iterations, estimating LOEs, holding weekly code review sessions, and mentoring team on best practices/standards to produce quality/maintainable code
- Migrated 400k accounts from Stream to NRG's system; this involved creating migration jobs utilizing Bash/PHP/MySQL and developing database views/stored procedures to retrieve historical customer data
- Led team on initiative to upgrade system PHP version from 5.2.x to 5.4.x
- Developed REST and SOAP APIs to provide customer information to Interactive Voice Response (IVR) System using .NET/PHP
- Added support for Free Nights and Free Weekends offerings; this consisted on updating CIS1 billing engine, product offering API, and web UI used by back office for telephonic enrollments/renewals
- Assisted with data analysis using Azure SQL DB and MySQL
- Used Visual Studio Azure DevOps for iterations/sprints and followed agile/scrum methodologies

#### Stream Energy, Senior Software Developer

March 2016 - March 2018

- Supported and maintained Stream's Customer Information System for Texas (CIS1)
- Created web UI for back office to manage carbon offset offering using CSS/Javascript/jQuery
- Integrated SmartyStreets REST API into CIS1 for address validation
- Integrated SalesForce Marketing Cloud SOAP API into CIS1 to trigger/send emails
- Integrated CyberGroup REST API into CIS1 to retrieve Weekly Energy Reports emailed to customers
- Developed job to clean/redact sensitive information from customer data using PHP

## Stream Energy, Software Developer II

March 2015 - March 2016

- Supported and maintained Stream's Customer Information System for Texas (CIS1)
- Created web UI for call center to manage protections for various billing fees using CSS/Javascript/JQuery
- Developed a nightly batch job for Wholesale Forecasting (Energy Buying Estimation) using PHP
- Created job to assess customers leaving platform for early termination fee using PHP

#### Stream Energy, Software Developer I

August 2013 - March 2015

- Supported and maintained Stream's Customer Information System for Texas (CIS1)
- Worked bugs and UI enhancements assigned by team lead
- Created web UI for finance team to manage customers eligible to send to collections using CSS/Javascript/JQuery

## University of North Texas - Office of Sustainability, Software Developer Intern

May 2013 - August 2013

- Converted the Office of Sustainability's website from static HTML to Drupal content management system
- Designed sustainability t-shirt, which was printed on 10,000+ shirts and given to students at the UNT Earth Day Campus Festival

#### **Education**

University of North Texas, 2009 - 2013

Major: Bachelor of Science in Computer Science; Minor: Mathematics

Google Scholar, 2011 - 2012, https://students.googleblog.com/2011/05/announcing-2011-google-hispanic-college.html

Verizon Scholar, 2009 - 2010